是的 我还病着呢
Yes, I am still sick.
是的 我周六还得上班
Yes, I'm going to work on a Saturday.
这不是酒 这是感冒药
No, this is not wine. It is DayQuil.
掺了点昨晚的酒
With a little bit of last night's wine.
我那蠢弟弟在墨西哥
My stupid brother caught a cold
度蜜月时竟然感冒了
in Mexico on his honeymoon,
结果还传染了全家人
and it's made its way through the family.
我从不生病
I never get sick.
肯定是在沙滩上我的袜子湿了
I-I must've caught a chill on the beach
所以着了凉
when my socks got wet.
我的脚踝疼得很
My ankles burn.
坐飞机回家时 我的耳朵也开始疼了
It went to my ears on our flight home.
我可能是呻吟了几声
I may have moaned a bit.
被一个大哭的婴儿投诉说声音太大
A crying baby complained about me.
小卡从墨西哥给我带回了这玩意
Cam brought me this from Mexico,
还害我得了支气管炎 病了两周
along with two weeks of bronchitis.
真不知道哪个更糟糕
I don't know which is worse.
我被传染了眩晕症
It gave me the vertigo.
一穿高跟鞋就晕
I was too dizzy for high heels.
害我只能穿平底鞋
I had to wear flats.
真不知道别人穿着那种鞋是怎么走路的
I don't know how people can walk in those things.
我错过了烹饪营前两天的课程
I missed the first two days of culinary camp,
完全跟不上做浓缩醋和蛋白饼的进度
so I was hopelessly behind on all reductions and meringues.
试想他们给我起的绰号
You can imagine the nicknames.
我觉得"逗逼"这名字挺伤人的
I thought "amuse-douche" was particularly cruel.
我连着吐了三天
I threw up for three straight days.
真不知道模特们是怎么做到的
I don't know how models do it.
祝你今天会议成功 亲爱的
Knock 'em dead at the big meeting today, honey.
来个幸运之吻不
Kiss for good luck?
不行 我不能害你也生病
Oh, no! I'm not getting you sick.
这场感冒到我为止
This cold stops with me.
不然我昨晚为什么要跟卢克换床睡
Why do you think I swapped beds with Luke last night?
你换了吗
You did?
非常感谢你的背部按摩
Appreciate the back rub.
但我可不太喜欢被叫"自以为是小姐"
Not sure I love being called "Miss Thang."
不是吧
No!
大家好
Hey, everybody.
老爸
Hey, dad --
不是吧
Noooo.
米奇和小卡当时找不到婚礼摄像师
Mitch and Cam were stuck for a wedding videographer,
我就帮他们联系了一个拍专题广告的朋友
so I hooked them up with a friend who shoots infomercials.
算是他欠我的吧
He kind of owed me.
我明白你为什么称之为奇迹手套了
I can see why you call them "Miracle gloves."
我的头完全不疼了
My headache's completely gone.
他把录像给了我
He dropped off the video
今晚我们会在杰和歌洛莉亚家
for the big viewing party
开观影派对 所以我想提前看看
at Jay and Gloria's tonight, and I decided to preview it.
怎么了
What's wrong?
你看
Watch.
我就长话短说吧
I'm gonna keep it short
因为再过十分钟就要开球了
'cause I got a tee-time in 10 minutes.
天哪
Oh, God.
说来也巧
Kind of funny.
我父亲死于25年前的今天
My dad died 25 years ago today.
直接喷在蛋糕上了
Ew! Right on the cake.
我知道 你接着看
I know. Keep watching.
很高兴能用这一快乐时刻
...nice to replace that sad memory
代替那段伤心的记忆
with this happy one.
别告诉我米奇舅舅还喝了
Don't tell me uncle Mitch drinks it.
他当然喝了 一滴不剩
Of course he does -- every drop.
愿你的第一次婚姻和我的第二次一样幸福
May your first marriage be as goods my second.
敬新郎们
To the grooms.
等等 我收回
Wait a minute. I take that back.
敬我的儿子们
To my sons.
你为什么就不能遮住嘴呢
Why didn't you just cover your mouth?
最后遮住了
Oh, I finally did.
你知道这意味着什么吗
You know what this means?
我才是第一个生病的人
I'm patient zero.
我还以为我是过敏
What I thought were allergies
却导致了全家人挨个病倒了
started the cold that brought the whole family down!
不能让任何人知道这件事
No one can ever know about this --
尤其是发生约塞米蒂国家公园那件事之后
Not after what happened in Yosemite.
粉眼末日
The pink-eye apocalypse.
-有只白眉山雀 -在哪儿
- A mountain chickadee! - Where?
每个人轮流看一眼
Take a look and send it down the line.
在哪儿 你在哪儿看到的 我想看看
Where? Where do you see it? I want to see.
就在那儿 在那儿 那儿呢
Oh, right there! Right there! Right there!
我整整花了一年才赢回
It took me a whole year to earn back
家人的尊重和崇拜
the respect and admiration of my family.
这个嘛
Well...
但还有六小时就要放映了
But it's six hours to the screening,
我得把打喷嚏的画面都剪掉
and I have to edit out all those sneezes
还不能毁了杰的演讲
without ruining Jay's speech.
所以得用上特效
That means special effects,
还得盖上绿屏
that means overlapping green screen.
我在说什么呢 那是不可能的啊
What am I saying?! It's impossible!
很抱歉 老爸
I'm sorry, dad.
不 你做得对
No, you're right.
不能再像个小姑娘一样发牢骚了
It's time to stop whining like a little girl
要爷们儿点
and man up!
穿上紧身衣
Let's put on our unitards!
曼尼 他最近踢丢了很多踢球得分
And Manny -- he's been missing a lot of kicks lately.
可能会害我们输掉比赛啊
He could cost us a game.
我可能得把他换下场
I may have to bench him.
教练总得做最有利于队伍的安排
A coach has to do what's best for the team.
家族忠诚对你来说一点不重要吗
Does family loyalty mean nothing to you, Mitchell?
更别说我还得面对愤怒的杰和歌洛莉亚
Not to mention I'd be facing the wrath of Jay and Gloria.
那你就让他上场
Well, then you should play him.
冒着牺牲我们3比0的完美战绩吗
And risk our perfect 3-0 record
这可是我当橄榄球队教练的第一年
in my first year as the varsity football coach,
本可以成为我进入大学工作
when this could be a stepping-stone
获得事业成功的垫脚石呢
to a college job or who knows what else?
灰姑娘一般的故事啊
You know, it's basically a cinderella story.
至少你服装是有了
Well, at least you have the outfit for it.
你到底还要不要帮我了
Are you gonna help me or not?
不好意思 好吧
I'm sorry. Um...okay.
也许你可以...
Well, maybe what you could do is --
我可以...尽教练之责
You know what I could do... is coach.
曼尼只是处于低潮期
You know, Manny's just in a slump.
他缺乏自信
You know, he's lacking confidence.
这并不容易 但我可以搞定这事
It's not gonna be easy, but I could pull this off.
对于灰姑娘的戏服 你也是这样说的
That's what you said about the Cinderella costume,
两小时后我们就给汽车俱乐部打了电话
and two hours later, we were calling the auto club.
我们要去后院了
We're going in the backyard.
去识别昆虫
To identify insects.
我爱死了
Oh, I love that.
是我干的
I did that.
希德妮·巴洛 跟我家莉莉一样有天赋
Sydney Barrow -- like my Lily, a gifted child,
多亏了我来做媒 她成了莉莉的新朋友
and, thanks to a little matchmaking, her new friend.
帮一个天才儿童
Yeah, i-it can be challenging
找玩伴 是很有挑战性的
finding playmates for an exceptional child.
我无意吹嘘
I don't mean to brag,
但那就是我儿时没有朋友的原因
but that's why I didn't have any friends.
艾伦 我让克莱尔去见你
Yeah, Alan, I'm sending Claire to meet with you.
我要去看我儿子的比赛
I got my kid's game.
是啊 他是踢球的
Yeah, he's the kicker.
可能全靠他得分呢
Could all come down to him.
放松点
Yeah, take it easy.
别那样说
Don't talk like that.
瞧 你让他好紧张
Look. You're stressing him out.
你紧张吗
You're stressed out?
有点
A little.
很好 因为压力是橄榄球的一部分
Good! 'Cause stress is all part of football.
如果你没吐在嘴里
If you're not throwing up in your mouth,
那就不对
you're not doing it right.
别理杰 宝贝
Ay. Don't pay attention to Jay, papi.
你会表现出色的
You're gonna be great.
你是我完美的小天使
You're my perfect little angel boy.
几个小时后比赛才开始
There's still a few hours left before game time.
我想我还是去床底下躺会儿吧
I think I'll just go lie down under my bed for a little while.
看见你做的好事了吗
You see what you do to him?
他没事 紧张挺好的
He's fine. Nerves are good.
有次在季后赛前
Just before a playoff game one time,
我拔下了一整条眉毛
I pulled out a whole eyebrow.
克莱尔 怎么了
Hey, Claire. What's up?
我发烧了 你个带病的混蛋
My fever, you orange jackass.
好吧
Oh. Okay.
显然你传染上了我的感冒
So, obviously, you have my cold now.
大家的第一症状好像都是憎恨
Everybody's first symptom seems to be hate.
多喝点水 在床上躺两天
Just pound the liquids, two days in bed.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
我可没两天时间
I don't have two days.
实际上
As a matter of fact,
我现在就要去参加客户会议
I have to go to a client meeting right now.
为什么
Why?
因为我有工作 人们指望着我呢
Because I have a job and people are counting on me.
不 是有人指望着你吧
Oh. No. Someone's counting on you.
这又是你和爸爸的事儿 你总是
This is about you and dad and how you just
喜欢当他的强悍小超女
love being his toughy-tough little supergirl
从来不请病假待在家
who never stays home sick,
手指断了
won a tennis tournament
都举不起来了
with a broken finger
还赢得了网球锦标赛冠军
that she couldn't even hold up.
我现在就举着中指呢
I'm holding it up now.
老爸的肯定是治不好你的
Daddy's approval is not the medicine that you need.
你何不直接给他打电话 告诉他
Why don't you just call him and tell him
你没法去开会了
that you can't take the meeting,
超级无敌女汉子姐
old toughy-tough-super-tough?
你为什么跟我吵起来了
Why are you trying to turn this into a fight?
我打电话来是骂你害我生病的
I called to yell at you for getting me sick.
爱你 拜拜
Love you. Bye.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
鸡 狗
Chicken, dog.
就差那么一点
Oh, so close.
该我了
My turn.
鸡 鸡
Chicken, chicken.
狗 狗
Dog, dog.
野山羊 野山羊
Ibex, ibex!
瞧你玩得多好
Oh, look at you go!
太久以来
For far too long,
莉莉的朋友们都无法挑战她
Lily's friends just haven't challenged her.
一直以来她的朋友都是吃胶水
It's been this endless procession of paste-eating,
尿不进马桶 找不到鞋子的傻孩子
toilet-missing shoe-losers.
但这俩人一起
But these two together --
她们提高了对方的水平
they raise each other's game.
*我想知道你是什么*
*How I wonder what you are*
好棒 莉莉
So good, Lily.
我会弹 但我不太会唱
I can play, but I don't really sing.
没关系 没有谁能擅长一切...
That's okay. Everybody can't be good at every--
二爸 我的鞋子呢
Daddy, where's my shoe?
曼尼 深呼吸
Okay, Manny, take a deep breath.
想象球垂直飞起来
Picture it going through the uprights.
简单点 看着球 抬起肩膀
Keep it simple -- eyes on the ball, shoulders up,
看见你的脚踢到球 把球踢飞
see your foot hit it, drive through the ball.
完成目标
Finish at your target!
这次更简单了
Even simpler this time --
用你的脚踢球
kick the ball with your foot.
上一次接触得不错
Great contact on that last one.
这次对准球
This time, aim for the ball.
这次认真点
Okay, this time, like you mean it.
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
曼尼 听着
Okay, Manny, look...
跟你说这话可不容易
There's no easy way to tell you this.
好啊 曼尼
Hola, Manny!
但我真的很喜欢
But, um... I, uh, really like the way
你的队服保持得这么干净
you're keeping your uniform clean.
用颜色保鲜的漂白剂 教练
Color-safe bleach, coach.
比赛时你会没事的
You'll be fine during the game.
拿出你去年暑假戒掉含糖饮料的势头来
Kick it like you kicked sugary drinks last summer.
好
Okay.
我看见训练的情况了
So, I saw the practice.
不怎么好
Not very good.
我很高兴你看到了 因为
I'm so glad you saw that, because --
他是为了在赛前
He's getting all the bad kicks
把所有烂球都踢完了
out of the way before the game!
他太棒了 好酷 曼尼
He's so good! Bravo, Manny!
加油 教练
Go get 'em, coach.
你也是
You too.
不
Oh, no.
我已经染上了小卡的耳塞
I'd already had Cam's clogged ears,
我爸的支气管炎
my dad's bronchitis,
下一条症状来得太是时候了
and then there it was, right on schedule --
歌洛莉亚的眩晕症
Gloria's vertigo.
我就是铁打的也不行了
Even I have my limits.
打给爸爸
Call dad.
保罗·路德是一位美国影视演员
Paul Rudd is an American film and television actor.
闭嘴
Shut up.
打给 爸爸
Call... dad!
宝贝女儿 你怎么样了
Hey, honey. How you doing?
我到酒店了
I'm at the hotel,
我真的很努力克服感冒的不适
and I'm really fighting this cold.
感冒这种小病难不倒你
Well, then, that cold doesn't stand a chance, huh?
我的小女超人是不可战胜的
Nothing stops my little supergirl.
是的
Yeah.
怎么了
What's up?
没什么 我只是
Nothing. I just...
我想告诉你这件事包在我身上
I wanted you to know that I'm on this, dad.
我从来不怀疑这一点
I never doubted that, honey.
是吗
Yeah.
休息厅在哪
Where's the lounge?
最后面
At the far end.
好的
Perfect.
我还记得你大一的时候
I remember your junior year,
你为了那场锦标赛可是拼了命一样
you played so tough through that tournament.
什么比赛来着 曲棍球吧
What was that? Uh.. .field hockey.
橄榄球
Rugby.
对
Right, and, uh,
你还把脚踝扭伤了
well, you sprained your ankle.
差点就成了骨裂
Could have been a hairline fracture.
那就更棒了
That's even better.
可你一点事没有 继续紧跟着球跑
But it didn't stop you. You rolled right through it.
对
Yeah.
我那天感觉特别自豪
I was a pretty proud papa that day.
好的 够了
Okay, stop!
好吧 我把她说害羞了
All right. I'm embarrassing her.
今晚见 乖女儿
I'll see you tonight, honey.
再见
Bye.
艾伦
Alan.
-你好 克莱尔 -你好
- Hey, Claire. - Hey.
-好久不见 -就是啊
- It's been ages. - Yeah.
你应该饿了吧
I hope you're hungry.
我在楼顶的
I got us a table
旋转餐厅订了张桌子
at the revolving rooftop restaurant.
不
Oh, no.
克莱尔
Claire?
这里刚好是我对着蛋糕打喷嚏之前
Here I am right before the cake sneeze.
看起来像在大笑 对吧
It looks like I'm cracking up, right?
从这里 我们用绿色背景拍摄一幕
So from here, we'll jump to a green-screen
你也在大笑的样子
shot of you laughing, too.
然后把你剪切到
Then I'll take that and drop it into
一大桌人的图像里面去
a pre-existing shot of a table full of people.
超简单
Easy!
笑起来吧
And we are laughing.
再大一点
Bigger.
想象我学尤达走进蜘蛛网的样子
Like when I do Yoda walking into a spider web.
就是这个
Nailed it!
如果大笑是最好的良药
If laughter's the best medicine,
那你就是葡萄味的抗过敏贴
then you're grape-flavored triaminic.
接下来要拍摄我听杰演讲时的镜头
Okay, now I need some footage of me reacting to Jay's speech
来替换朝香槟打喷嚏这一段
to replace the champagne sneeze,
然后把这段接到另一张一大桌人的图像里
and I'll just drop that into another table full of people.
对于杰的演讲 我应该有什么反应
How would I react to Jay's speech?
表现出感动的样子
Give me "Touched."
悲伤
Now sad.
再悲伤点
Sadder.
加油 感情再深点
Come on. Dig deep.
就想像我要去上大学了
Think about me going off to college.
你怎么在笑
Why are you smiling?
我没想到你能考上
Uh, I-I didn't think you'd get in.
我不想把一个大好的周六晚上
I don't want to waste a Saturday night
浪费在看视频上
Watching some video.
我们待在家里租个电影看吧
Let's just stay home and rent a movie.
两件事 电影也是视频
Okay, two things -- a movie is a video,
还有你不想去外公家就是因为
and the only reason you don't want to go to grandpa's
你害怕见到安迪
is because you're avoiding Andy.
害怕 才不是呢
Avoid? I don't --
我
I --
我不想谈这个话题
I'm not having this conversation.
拜托 你从婚礼那天开始就躲着他
Oh, please. You've been dodging him since the wedding.
是你让我离他远一点的
You told me to stay away from him.
我只是说除非你真的喜欢他
I just meant don't lead him on
不然别招惹人家
unless you really like him.
对 你说得没错
Yes, and you were right,
所以为了保护他 我一直跟他保持距离
so I've been keeping my distance to protect him.
你这么想还是挺成熟的
Well, that's actually really mature of you.
我长得这么辣 当然得更负责任一点
With great hotness comes great responsibility.
恢复本性了
There she is.
如果曼尼能踢好这球 我们就领先了
If Manny makes this one, we go ahead.
压力很大
Lot of pressure.
我打赌他紧张得胃里泛酸
I'll bet he's chewing on his own stomach acid right now.
有点太多愁善感了 我就是挺怀念的
Sorry to be so sentimental. I just miss it.
曼尼 大力踢球
Manny, kick this one hard!
不愧是我的孩子
That's my boy!
实际上 是我们家孩子
Actually, that's our boy.
那才是我们家孩子
Oh, that's our boy.
关键时刻
Moment of truth.
看到任何小问题 都请指出来
If you see even the tiniest problem, point it out.
我父亲死于25年前的今天
My dad died 25 years ago today.
这跟我想象的场景不太一样
That did not land quite the way I'd hoped.
小卡 米奇尔
Cam, Mitchell...
愿你的第一次婚姻和我的第二次一样幸福
May your first marriage be as happy as my second.
敬新郎们
To the grooms.
等等 我收回
Wait a minute. I take that back.
这太糟了
Oh, that's so bad.
敬我的儿子们
To my sons.
杰
Oh. Jay.
好吧 我有几点建议
O...kay. I have a few notes.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
我们还有一个小时就要放这个视频了
We have to show this thing in an hour!
你知道换作是你会怎么跟我说吗
You know what you'd tell me?
放原来的视频 勇于承担后果
Show the real video and take your lumps.
我不想那样
I don't wanna.
那是我会说的话
That's what I would say.
然后你会跟我说
And then you would tell me,
你也许不想那样做
"You might not want to do it,
但你必须做正确的事
"but you have to do what's right.
那会使你
"And that will make you
从零号病患变为英雄病患
go from patient zero to patient hero."
该死 我说得太有道理了
Damn it, I've got a point.
这么聪明一个人怎么会打那么多喷嚏呢
How does someone so smart sneeze on so many things?
画完了
Finished!
来看看
Let's see.
不好意思 这是有人抢劫了画廊吗
Oh. I'm sorry, but did someone rob an art gallery?
因为这简直太美
Because this is absolutely beau--
画完了
Done!
好吧
Okay.
我们应该在上面写上名字
We should probably put your names on those
不然该分不出来谁是谁的了
so we can remember whose is whose.
下一个活动
Next activity.
莉莉知道所有的首府
Okay, Lily knows all the capitals.
爸爸
Dad!
没关系的 宝贝
It's all right, honey.
第一个是奥尔巴尼[纽约州首府]
The first is Albany.
接下来是
Then there's...?
我以为你说的是各国的首府
Ohh! I thought you meant world capitals.
阿尔及利亚 阿尔及尔
Algeria, Algiers.
安哥拉
Angola --
你还真是爱显摆自己有学问啊
Oh. Well, you're just a little know-it-all, aren't ya?
天哪 非常抱歉
Oh, my god. I am so sorry. I -- oh.
好了 希德妮 忘记我说的话吧宝贝
Okay. Sydney, forget that I said that, okay, honey?
不行 因为我记忆力超群
I can't! I have a photographic memory!
你把我的朋友搞哭了
You made my friend cry!
不 我不是有意的
No, I didn't mean to --
天哪
Oh, boy.
你是故意的
You did that on purpose!
不 不 我不是
No, no. I-I don't think I did.
天哪 你妈妈来了
Oh, gosh. And there's your mother.
希德妮 宝贝 不能再哭了 好吗
Sydney, sweetheart, we got to stop crying, okay?
你没事
You're okay.
我的表卡住了
Oh. Now my watch is caught.
没事 轻轻拉 轻轻拉
All right, little pull. Little pull!
没事的 没事的
It's fine! It's fine!
Oh, it's fine. It's fine.
-我们玩得太开心了 -那就好
- We had so much fun. - Oh, good.
希德妮 宝贝 你在哭吗
Sydney, honey, are you crying?
他把我的画毁了 还拉我头发
He ruined my picture and pulled my hair!
只是个小意外
Just little accidents.
他还说我爱显摆学问
And he called me a know-it-all!
什么样的人会这样说一个六岁的孩子
What kind of a person calls a 6-year-old a know-it-all?
她还比你小一岁是吗
She's a year younger than you?
我是不是不该来
Should I not have come?
安迪会不会觉得很怪
Oh, is it gonna be weird for Andy?
我不应该穿得这么好看的
I shouldn't have dressed so cute.
把毛衣换给我
Hey, switch sweaters with me.
做你自己吧
Just be yourself.
这样他能最快速度忘掉你
It's the surest way for him to get over you.
好吧 谢谢
Okay, thanks.
-小卡叔叔 -你好
- Hey, uncle Cam. - Hey.
我的天 你来了太好了
Oh, my gosh. I'm so glad you're here.
你得和莉莉谈谈
You got to talk to Lily.
她不和我讲话了 因为
She's not speaking to me because --
我有更大的问题
I have bigger problems.
我还没跟你说我的问题呢
I haven't even told you what mine is yet.
我让曼尼坐冷板凳了
I benched Manny.
我担心杰和歌洛莉亚会生我的气
I'm worried Jay and Gloria are mad at me.
-他们说什么了吗 -没有
- Have they said anything? - No.
我只听到他们对我说了"你好"
All I've gotten from them so far is "Hola"
还有"这瓶威士忌不分享"
and "That scotch is not for company."
天哪 菲尔 那是婚礼视频吗
Oh, my gosh, Phil, is that the wedding video?
我们太期待了
Oh, we are so excited to see it.
我也很期待给你们看
I'm so excited to show you guys!
快去客厅 把所有电线都剪了
Get in the media closet. Cut every wire.
爸爸 冷静点
Dad, get ahold of yourself.
你说得对
You're right.
我说了"你说得对"
I said, "You're right"!
对不起 我手臂已经准备到位了
Sorry. I already had it loaded up.
大家都来吃晚饭吧
Everybody come to dinner.
然后我们就看婚礼视频
Then we watch the wedding movie.
谢谢你们的招待
Hey, thank you guys so much for hosting.
我希望曼尼的事你们不会有什么想法
And I hope there's no hard feelings about Manny.
你是教练 你不能徇私
You're the coach. You can't play favorites.
正是
Exactly.
听你这么说我就放心了
I am so relieved to hear you say that.
不 不 我们坏了一把椅子
No, no, no. One of our chairs is broken.
来 我为你准备了特殊的位子
Come. I have a special seat for you.
米奇尔
Mitchell!
她让我坐冷板凳
She benched me.
不 你又赢了我
No! You beat me again!
那你真是太尴尬了
Well, this is embarrassing for you.
你好 陌生人
Oh. Hey, stranger.
我故意让他赢的
I let him win.
你怎么样
How you been?
很好 很好 就是有点忙
Oh, good, good. Just busy.
我想应该打个招呼 毕竟时间挺长了
I figured I'd say hi. It's been a while.
是啊
I know, right?
我也一直在忙着照顾这个小家伙
I've been busy, too, between this little guy
还要回去探望家人
and visiting my family back home.
我 我真的很高兴你能过来
I'm -- I'm really glad you came by.
之前还担心我们之间会比较尴尬
I was afraid things got, like...weird
鉴于上次碰面时候的事
last time we saw each other.
是啊 那件事 我真的...
Y-yeah, about that -- um, I rea--
我就知道
Oh! I knew it.
有时候我就是个大蠢蛋
I am such a goober sometimes.
贝丝让我手足无措
I was just confused about Beth,
我以为你在向我传达某种信号
and I thought you were sending me some signals,
这样想真是太傻了
which is so stupid.
希望我的举动没有吓到你
I hope I didn't, like, creep you out or something.
你不该这样想自己
You shouldn't feel stupid.
你当时很脆弱 而我在婚礼上
You know, you were vulnerable, I was at a wedding,
所有人都是基佬
everybody was super-gay,
根本没有人看我一眼
and nobody was looking at me.
也许我确实向你传达了某种信号
I probably did send you a signal.
对你造成的困惑我表示歉意
I'm sorry if I gave you the wrong idea.
不用介意
Don't worry about it.
很高兴我们没做出更进一步的举动
I'm just glad we didn't take it any further.
很明显 我们两个实在不配
Because clearly, we are wrong for each other.
完全同意 我们还是做朋友比较好
Totally. We are way better as friends.
没错
Way!
难以想象我们亲吻会怎么样
Like, imagine if we kissed or something.
那一定会是场灾难
Ha! That would've been a disaster.
一场大灾难
A huge disaster.
你会被摧毁的
You would've been destroyed.
是啊 什么
Yeah -- what?
乔 你头发怎么都白了
Whoa, Joe. What's with the snow on the roof?
你看起来老得像个总统
You're aging like a president.
克莱尔发信息让我们先吃
Claire texted to start.
她会晚些过来
She's going to be a little late.
真抓狂
Well, that's crazy.
我们应该等她一起
We should wait for her
不如改天再看婚礼录像吧
and watch the wedding video some other time.
不用 我们开吃吧
No, no, no. Let's eat.
我不怎么饿
I'm not very hungry.
我嘴里依然残留着失败的味道
I still have the taste of failure in my mouth.
坐下 这是家庭聚餐
Sit down. This is a family dinner.
我们要一起吃
We all eat together.
你们那有土豆吗 我闻到土豆的味道了
Are there potatoes? I smell potatoes.
给你的 宝贝儿
Here you go, sweetheart.
我不吃
You eat it.
莉莉 没那么糟
Lily, it wasn't that bad.
你手表上还夹着我朋友的头发呢
You still got my friend's hair in your watch!
她会回来的
She's coming back.
你脑子进水了吗
What were you thinking with that playdate?
我是出于对孩子的保护
I was feeling protective.
那孩子让莉莉很难堪
That girl made Lily feel bad.
也许是让你很难堪吧
Or did she make you feel bad?
我的确不喜欢
I didn't love it.
新手父母通常都会这样的
That happens with all first-time parents.
总认为自己的孩子是最聪明的
We think our kids are the best or the smartest.
曾经很长时间 我们也那样看待海莉
For the longest time, that's how we felt about Haley.
"很长时间" 真的吗
"The longest time"? Really?
你不能迫使孩子
You can't force your kids
一直活在你不切实际的期待当中
to live up to your unreal expectations.
他们并不完美 但你依然爱他们
They're not perfect, but you love them anyway.
对大人一样适用 也许更应该如此
Also applies to adults -- probably more so.
我就是这样的 是不是
That is what I'm doing, isn't it?
杰在曼尼踢球这件事上一贯如此
Jay does it all the time with Manny's football.
你们看他 因为担心让杰失望
Look at him -- he's so upset of disappointing him
今天连饭都不想吃了
that he won't eat today.
我们不要跑题好不好
Let's keep in mind what's important here --
我们在生小卡的气
We're mad at Cam.
你一向如此
You have always been like this.
你给儿女们太大压力
You put so much pressure into your kids
最后导致他们崩溃
that they fall into pieces.
我从没给过他们无法承受的压力
I never put more pressure on my kids than they can handle.
别生气 爸
Oh, don't be mad, dad.
对不起 我尽力了 真的尽力了
I'm sorry. I tried. I really -- I tried.
咚咚咚 又是我
Knock, knock. Me again.
好啊
Hey, you.
让我快速跟进一下
Hey. So, uh, quick follow-up.
你刚才说如果我们亲吻我会被摧毁
Um, when you said I would be destroyed if we had kissed,
那到底是什么意思
what exactly did you mean by that?
天哪
Oh, gosh.
让你很困惑是吧
I guess that is confusing, huh?
是的
Yeah.
我的意思是你会被我迷得神魂颠倒
I just meant that you would've been emotionally ruined.
什么
What?!
是的 我也不明白自己怎么会这样
Yeah. I don't understand it myself,
但我就是有这种魅力
but there's a lot of heat coming off of this.
女孩都无法抗拒我这样的男孩
Girls do not get over this guy.
不敢说自己是毒品 不过
I'm not calling myself a drug, but --
不好意思 贝丝不是甩了你十几次吗
I'm sorry. Hasn't Beth broken up with you, like, 10 times?
可她依然迫切地想跟我复合
She's dying to get back with me, though.
可能就跟戒毒的感觉差不多
I wouldn't say it's withdrawal, but --
告诉你吧 我才是让男孩念念不忘的
For the record, guys don't get over me, okay?
最新数据 我有三个追求者
At last count, I have three stalkers.
其中一个甚至把我的样子喷刷在他的车上
One of them has my face spray-painted on his van.
他画的时候我就得一直杵在那
I had to stand there forever while he did it!
好吧
Okay.
我的意思并不是如果我们亲吻
I didn't mean to imply that if we kissed,
我就不会迷上你
it wouldn't affect me.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
你那么漂亮 我根本配不上你
You are so pretty and so out of my league.
那会颠覆我的整个世界
It would've... rocked my world.
那好吧
Okay, then.
只是会更让你疯狂 就是这样
It just would've hit you harder. That's all.
普里契特先生 你该洗澡了
Mr. Pritchett! Your bath awaits!
今天要搓搓小屁股 准备好了吗
Are you prepared for a bum-scrubbing today, sir?
哦不
Ohhh, no.
我说错话了 是不是
I said something wrong, didn't I?
没有
No.
不 是我在犯傻
No, I'm just being stupid.
重点是 我们的关系未受影响 对吧
The point is is that, you know, we're good, right?
那当然了
You betcha.
来吧 别这么一本正经的
Aw, come on. Don't be so formal.
来吧 小子
Come here, you.
我答应要带这个小家伙去洗泡泡浴的
I promised this little dude a bubble beard.
来抱抱
Come here.
别就此成了陌生人 好吗
Don't be a stranger, okay?
亲爱的 稍微自私一点吧
Honey, be a little selfish here.
你现在的健康状况完全看不了这视频啊
You are not up for watching this video.
你都这样了为什么还要出门啊
Why were you even out of the house like this?
因为我是个强悍的女汉子
Because I'm your toughy-tough supergirl.
是没错 但也没必要因此拿...
Yes, you are, but that's no reason to risk you--
离食物远一点
Away from the food!
我们能下次再举行吗
Can we catch this again?
你就是经常做这种事
This is exactly what you do!
对他的亲生女儿也如此
To his own daughter.
所以你们要正确看待我让曼尼坐冷板凳这事
Kind of puts me benching Manny in perspective.
对了 你们那边有酱汁吗...
Also, is there a sauce going around or...
小卡 你让我坐冷板凳是对的
Cam, you were right to bench me.
我踢得太烂了
I stunk out there.
沉冤洗清了
Vindicated!
但那不是因为杰
But not because of Jay.
是因为你 妈
It's you, mom.
什么
What?!
现场火药味儿太浓
Tensions are running high.
我觉得我们都该回家避难
I think we should all go home.
我从来不会担心让杰失望
I've never worried about disappointing Jay.
他知道我体育很差劲
He knows I'm terrible at sports.
我第一天就说了
Said it from day 1.
这孩子身上唯一协调的部分就是他的衣服
Only thing coordinated about this kid was his outfits.
你老叫我完美的小天使什么的
The way you call me your perfect little angel boy and stuff,
我总觉得我会让你失望
I just feel like I'm letting you down.
曼尼 我真的很抱歉
Ay, Manny, I'm so sorry.
你永远不会让我失望的
You could never let me down,
因为你是我的完美...
because you're my per--
你挺好的
You're okay.
我把婚礼视频插进播放机了
I cued up the wedding video.
是你独立完成的吗
All by yourself?
我们一起去看吧 你们觉得怎么样
Let's watch it. What do you say?
-好啊 -我们走
- Okay. - Let's go.
我好紧张
I'm nervous.
-现在这种时候合适吗 -当然
- Is this- is this a good time? - Yes.
感觉...那好吧
It feels like -- o-okay.
我们现在就去看吧 快点
Let's go now. Come on.
我先坦白交代
F-full disclosure --
视频中的大家可能看上去并不是太好
Everybody may not look their best in this video.
好得很
It's good.
我们就该看清真实的自我
It's about time we all start seeing ourselves as who we really are,
而不是我们努力想成为的那种人
not who we're trying to be
-或别人期待我们成为的那种人 -对
- or who other people want us to be. - Right.
我想说下 那是台非常复杂的机器
See, now, that is a very complicated machine.
她是个小天才
She is a genius.
你这头开的就不对
Not a good start.
放吧 莉莉
Hit it, Lily.
这会对你有好处的
This is gonna be good for you.
我这会儿可不喜欢你
I don't like you right now.
天啊
Oh, god.
那是 那是我在跳舞吗
Is that -is that my dancing?
我竟然是那个样子的吗
Is that what I look like?
别 好吧 那可真搞笑啊
No, no. Okay, that's really funny.
快进 快点
Fast forward. Come on.
那真的好甜蜜 小卡
That's actually really sweet, Cam.
那是我的哭泣脸吗
Is that my crying face?
真的好丑啊 怎么从来没人告诉过我啊
Oh, it's hideous! Why hasn't anyone told me?!
天啊 我现在又是这副表情了 对吧
Oh, god, I'm doing it right now, aren't I?
把遥控器给我
Give me that.
恭喜啊 米奇和小卡
Congratulations, Mitch and Cam!
瞧瞧我穿那条裙子的样子
Look at me in that dress!
我看上去美翻了
I look gorgeous!
我要倒回去再看一遍
Give me rewind!
妈 瞧瞧你倚靠着那个吧台的样子
Mom, look at you holding on to that bar.
你那时候也患了眩晕症呢
You had vertigo there, too.
是啊 没错
Yeah, I sure did.
我们没必要老看这一段的
You know, we don't have to linger on that.
哎呀妈
Oh, mom!
大家好 我有几句话想说
Hey, everybody. I want to say something.
一身汗 搞毛啊
All that sweat. What the hell?!
我看上去像是刚跟鲸鱼紧密搂抱过
I look like I had shamu in a headlock!
我觉得我要吐了
I think I'm gonna throw up.
是啊 我也是 我太令人恶心了
Yeah, you and me both. I'm disgusting!
不不不 是海莉的恶心病 天啊
No, no, no, no, no. It's Haley's nausea. Oh, god!
我就长话短说吧
I'm gonna keep it short.
是啊 务必这样
Yeah, you will.
那个屋子里有120位宾客
120 people in that room,
却没人提醒我要把胳膊放下来
and no one told me to put my arm down!
我有个好主意
I have an idea, actually.
不如让我重新剪辑这个视频
Why don't I re-edit the video
把那些尴尬的部分都剪掉吧
And cut out the embarrassing parts?
那麻烦吗
Is that a problem?
一点都不麻烦
Not at all!
-那太好了 -轻松搞定
- That's great! - Done!
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much.
我知道你对着蛋糕打喷嚏了
I know you sneezed on the cake.
没人喜欢无所不知的小孩
No one likes a know-it-all!
米奇尔
Mitchell.
快上床来啊
Come to bed.
你不打算睡觉了吗
Aren't you ever gonna sleep?
不 我觉得我睡不着了
No. No, I don't think I'am.
米奇尔
Mitchell.